Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Peter and Leona Newell Papers, 1840-1985; Series I; 11.8; (20 boxes)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Stocks and certificates
      - American and Mexican Mines Company, 1912-13, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 245)
      - Broken Hills Mining Company of Nevada, 1909, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 246)
      - Claude M. Nankivel Company, 1917, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 247)
      - Grant Oil Company, 1901, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 248)
      - Iroquois Porcupine Mining Co., Ltd., 1911-12, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 249)
      - Omaha-Wyoming Oil Company, 1904-40 (Box 12, Folder 250)
      - Pathfinder Company, 1917, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 251)
      - Pelican Mining Milling and Power Co., 1912 (Box 12, Folder 252)
      - Swastika-Mountain-Top-Mining Company, 1911-15, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 253)
      - Other correspondence re: stocks and certificates, 1915, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 254)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera, 1884-1922 (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - CREATIVE WRITINGS
    The subseries contains manuscript and typescript drafts of Newell's writings for his illustrations. The writings are arranged by: Comics and Captions; Essays; Poems and Rhymes; Short Stories; and Theatrical Works.
    - Comics and Captions
      - "The Musician Wins a Bride" typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 256)
      - "Old Bill Nickle" manuscripts with sketches, ca. 1921 (Box 13, Folder 257)
      - "Old Saw Simpson" typescripts with sketches, ca. 1920 (Box 13, Folder 258)
        See also: Box 14, Folder 318
      - Topsys & Turvys manuscript, ca. 1893 (Box 13, Folder 259)
      - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 13, Folder 260)
    - Essays
      - "Elegy on a Mosquito" "Hero Worship" manuscripts, ca. 1879 (Box 13, Folder 261)
      - "An Exploded Ghost" corrected typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 262)
      - Fables (16 stories) typescripts and manuscripts (Box 13, Folder 263)
      - "The First Grindstone" "The First Microscope" corrected typescripts (Box 13, Folder 264)
      - "The Inalienable Right" typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 265)
      - "Jimmy" typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 266)
      - "Little Monologues" (5 stories) manuscript, corrected typescripts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 267)
      - "The Wood Family, carved by P. Newell" typescript, ca. 1911 (Box 13, Folder 268)
        See also: Series II, Box 187 and Series III, Box 245, Folders 3367-3368
    - Poems and Rhymes
      - Calendar poems for five months, ca. 1910 (Box 13, Folder 269)
      - typescripts with sketches
      - "Christmas in the Woods" manuscript with sketches, ca. 1891 (Box 13, Folder 270)
      - "Distortions" typescript with sketches, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 271)
        See also: Box 13, Folder 293
      - "A Great Thaw," corrected typescript with additions, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 272)
      - [The Hole Book] typescripts with annotations, ca. 1908 (Box 13, Folder 273)
      - "If I Should Go to War" typescript with sketch, ca. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 274)
      - ["Jungle-Jangle"] typescript, ca. 1909 (Box 13, Folder 275)
      - ["The Little Eye Folk"] corrected typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 276)
      - ["Lumox, the Grouch"] manuscript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 277)
      - "Not All Love Spring" manuscript and typescript, ca. 1890 (Box 13, Folder 278)
      - "Old Tige" corrected typescripts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 279)
      - "A Promotion" corrected typescript with sketches, ca. 1920 (Box 13, Folder 280)
      - "A Recitation For a Good Little Girl" typescripts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 281)
      - The Rocket Book galley proof sheets, [1912] (Box 13, Folder 282)
      - [Seasons] (variant poems with identical titles), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 283)
      - corrected typescripts
      - ["A Thaw Up In the Klondike"] manuscript with sketch (Box 13, Folder 284)
      - "Various Loves" typescript with annotations, corrections and sketches (Box 13, Folder 285)
      - Other titled short poems and rhymes manuscripts and typescripts with corrections and sketches (Box 13, Folder 286)
      - Other untitled short poems and rhymes manuscripts and typescripts with sketches (Box 13, Folder 287)
    - Short Stories
      - "Alice in Funnyland: Synopsis of scenario based on the Mad Tea Party in Alice in Wonderland " manuscript and typescript (Box 13, Folder 288)
      - [Alice in Funnyland:] "Synopsis of Scenario of Rabbit Hole episode in Alice in Wonderland " typescript with watercolor sketches (Box 13, Folder 289)
      - "Blowing Up a Ghost" corrected typescript, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 290)
      - "A Blowout in the Subway" corrected typescript with sketch, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 291)
      - "A Forty Second Street Earthworm" corrected typescript (Box 13, Folder 292)
      - [Untitled variation on the above two stories with the subway/cold cream theme] manuscript with typescript of poem "Distortions" on verso, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 293)
      - "The Little Eye People" manuscript, typescript and sketches, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 294)
      - [Spinning Totty and the North Pole] corrected typescript (pages 1-2 only) (Box 13, Folder 295)
      - "The True Account of the Adventures of Master T. Sylvester Boston (as related by himself)" typescript, missing pages 2-3, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 296)
      - [Untitled and unfinished story about a poor artist in New York] manuscript (Box 13, Folder 297)
      - Other untitled story ideas and drafts manuscripts (Box 13, Folder 298)
    - Theatrical Works
      - ["An Elastic Proposal"] typescript, [1906] (Box 13, Folder 299)
        See also: Box 11, Folder 210
      - "The Hypnotist: a Farcelet in One Actlet" typescript with sketch, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 300)
  - COMMISSIONED WORKS
    Contains samples of printed pieces, tearsheets, clippings and proofs of published illustrations and comics which are classified by intent: Books; Periodicals; Calendars; Corporate Projects and Advertisements; and Toys. Sketches, preparatory drawings and finished drawings for many of these projects can be found in Series II.
    - Books
      - Bangs, John Kendrick
        - Mr. Munchausen color plates, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 301)
        - Mr. Munchausen poster, 1901
          See: Oversize, Folder 3325
      - Carroll, Lewis
        - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland proofs, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 302)
        - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland dust jacket, ca. 1915 (Box 13, Folder 303)
        - Through the Looking Glass proofs, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 304)
        - Through the Looking Glass dust jacket proof, ca. 1915 (Box 13, Folder 305)
        - Photographs of drawings, 1901-03 (Box 13, Folder 306)
      - Carryl, Guy Wetmore
        - Fables for the Frivolous poster, 1898
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3326
      - Favorite Fairy Tales dust jacket proof, ca. 1915 (Box 13, Folder 307)
      - Newell, Peter
        - The Hole Book proofs and dust jacket, 1908 (Box 13, Folder 308)
        - Jungle-Jangle type proof and booklet, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 309)
        - Pictures and Rhymes cover proof, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 310)
        - A Shadow Show proofs, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 311)
        - The Slant Book proofs and pages, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 312)
        - Topsys and Turvys wood dummy with printed wrapper, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 313)
      - Stone, Stuart B.
        - The Kingdom of Why proofs, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 314)
      - Wells, Carolyn
        - Mother Goose's Menagerie proof, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 315)
    - Periodicals
      - Collier's
        - Newell drawing tearsheet, 1898
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3327
        - Benchley, Robert "The First Lesson" proofs, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 316)
      - Cosmopolitan Magazine
        - Colton, Arthur "The Kings of Maleta" tearsheets, ca. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 317)
      - Country Gentleman
        - Newell comics clippings, ca. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 318)
      - The Delineator
        - Johnson, Burges and Constance "Classic Poets" tearsheets, 1913
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3328
        - "Peter Newell's Movies", 1914
        - clippings and tearsheets
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3329
      - Everybody's Magazine
        - Thomas, Rowland "Octopodousa Ferox" tearsheets, ca. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 319)
      - Frank Leslie's Weekly
        - Newell drawing proof and tearsheet, 1891
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3330
      - The Graphic
        - Newell cartoon tearsheet, 1890
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3331
      - Harper's magazines, various
        - Newell comics clippings in scrapbook, 1881-ca. 1890 (Box 14, Folder 320)
        - Newell comics postcard, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 321)
      - Harper's Bazaar
        - Newell comics proofs, 1892-99 (Box 14, Folder 322)
        - Newell comics clippings and tearsheets, 1887-98 (Box 14, Folder 323)
        - Newell comics: Biddleby family proofs and tearsheets, 1894
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3332
        - Newell comics proofs and tearsheets, 1888-1911
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3333
      - Harper's Monthly Magazine
        - Newell comics clippings and tearsheets, 1893-1924 (Box 14, Folder 324)
        - Newell comics proofs, 1893-ca. 1910
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3334
        - Stockton, Frank "The Great Stone of Sardis" proofs and clippings, 1897 (Box 14, Folder 325)
        - Other authors proofs and tearsheets, 1898-1906, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 326)
      - Harper's Young People/Round Table
        - Newell comics and illustrations proofs and clippings, 1885-96 (Box 14, Folder 327)
        - Other authors proofs, clippings and tearsheets, 1891-98 (Box 14, Folder 328)
      - Harper's Weekly
        - Newell comics clippings, tearsheets and issue, 1885-1907 (Box 14, Folder 329)
        - Newell comics and covers proofs, clippings and tearsheets, 1892-1910
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3335
        - Newell comics "Columbia Exposition" series clippings and tearsheets, 1893
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3336
        - Other authors proofs and clippings, 1893-99 (Box 14, Folder 330)
      - The Ladies' Home Journal
        - "Alice in Wonderland" designs for sofa pillows and quilt, 1905 Aug-Sep
        - proofs and tearsheet
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3337
        - Other authors proof and full issue, 1905, 1910
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3338
      - The Ladies' World
        - Newell, Peter "Needledee and Needledum" tearsheet and full issue, 1914 Apr-May
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3339
      - McClure's Magazine
        - Browne, Porter Emerson "The Uncivil War" tearsheet, 1918 May
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3340
      - New York Herald Tribune, Sunday Magazine cover on full issue, 1905 Nov 5
        See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3341
      - Puck
        - Newell comic clipping, ca. 1910 (Box 14, Folder 331)
      - St. Nicholas
        - Newell comics proofs and tearsheet, 1892-1904, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 332)
        - "Inanimate Things Animated" proofs, 1892 Feb-Dec (Box 14, Folder 333)
        - "Inanimate Things Animated" proofs, 1893-1904 (Box 14, Folder 334)
      - Saturday Evening Post
        - Newell comics clippings, ca. 1915 (Box 14, Folder 335)
      - Scribner's Magazine
        - Walcott, E. A. "Gormley's Scoop" tearsheets, 1898 Aug (Box 14, Folder 336)
      - Woman's Home Companion
        - Newell comics and illustrations tearsheets, 1905-10
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3342
      - The Youth's Companion
        - Foster, Edna A. "The Children's Circus" tearsheet, 1902 Oct 9
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3343
      - Unidentified periodicals
        - Newell comics and illustrations proofs, 1890-ca. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 337)
        - Newell comics and illustrations clippings, 1884-ca. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 338)
        - Newell comics and illustrations tearsheets and proofs, 1890-ca. 1920
          See: Oversize, Box 242, Folder 3344
    - Calendars
      - Calendar for 1903 (2 pages), [1902] (Box 15, Folder 339)
      - "The Peter Newell Calendar for 1910", 1909 (Box 15, Folder 340)
      - with box
    - Corporate projects and advertisements
      - Charles E. Hires Company
        - Hires' Household Extract hangtag advertisement, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 341)
        - Hires' Root Beer broadside advertisements (6), 1906-14 (Box 15, Folder 342)
        - Hires' Root Beer hangtag advertisements (2), 1914 (Box 16, Folder 343)
        - Fragment of display prop portrait of "Josh Slinger", ca. 1906 (Box 16, Folder 344)
      - Excelsior Mills (Bushnell, IL?) illustration of mill, ca. 1883 (Box 16, Folder 345)
      - Illinois Agricultural Works catalogue with illustrations, ca. 1883 (Box 16, Folder 346)
      - Illinois College, Jacksonville, IL catalogue and letterhead with illustration of campus, ca. 1884 (Box 16, Folder 347)
      - Murphy Varnish Company "The Tinkling Banjo" novelty advertisement (2), ca. 1910 (Box 16, Folder 348)
      - Newell, Peter advertising card, Springfield, IL, [1883] (Box 16, Folder 349)
      - Pacific Coast Borax Company "The 20-Mule-Team Brigade: being a story in Jingles of the good works and adventures of the Famous "Twenty Mule Team" booklet, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 350)
      - Patrick-Duluth Woolen Mill advertising postcards (set of 4), ca. 1910 (Box 16, Folder 351)
      - Rogers, Peet and Company calendar for 1904 with biographical publicity brochure, [1903] (Box 16, Folder 352)
      - Salmagundi Club dinner program cover, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Toys
      - "The Kiddy Speller", 1920 (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - PUBLICITY AND WRITINGS ABOUT NEWELL
    Filed in chronological order within six sections: Biographical Dictionary Entries; Biographical Sketches, Profiles and Interviews; Mentions and Brief Articles; Reviews and Catalogues of Exhibitions; Reviews and Catalogues of Publications; and Parodies.
    - Biographical Dictionary Entries
      - Biographical Sketches of American Artists, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 355)
      - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 356)
      - Dictionary of American Biography, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 357)
        See also: Series VIII, Box 212, Folder 2848
      - Miscellaneous, 1903-26, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 358)
    - Biographical Sketches, Profiles and Interviews
      This section contains the most substantial published biographical material on Newell. Not included here, but equally as important, is the essay by John Kendrick Bangs published as an introduction to the book Peter Newell's Pictures and Rhymes (1900).
      - Lee, Albert "Peter Newell" in The Book Buyer, 1896 Jul (Box 17, Folder 359)
      - Armstrong, Regina "The New Leaders in American Illustration" in The Bookman, 1900 Jun (Box 17, Folder 360)
      - [Untitled short profile, unknown journal], [ca. 1901] (Box 17, Folder 361)
      - "Harper's Literary Gossip", 1901-03 (Box 17, Folder 362)
      - Wheelock, Matilda Henderson "Peter Newell As I Knew Him Twenty- Five Years Ago" typescript, [1902?] (Box 17, Folder 363)
      - "Peter Newell's Work" and, 1902 (Box 17, Folder 364)
      - "Peter Newell illustrates his idea of the glorious California climate", 1902 May 3
      - unidentified Los Angeles newspapers; "25 years ago today - from the Express, April 23, 1902" The Express, 1927 Apr 23
      - Young, Jeannette "Peter Newell" in Good Housekeeping, 1902 Apr (Box 17, Folder 365)
      - Sill, Louise Morgan "Mr. Newell's Latest Drawings" in Harper's Bazaar, 1902 Sep (Box 17, Folder 366)
      - "Peter Newell Tells of his Work as a Maker of Pictures" in Newark Sunday News, 1904 Apr 10
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3315
      - Bangs, John Kendrick
        - "An Appreciation of Peter Newell" in New York Herald and The Sunday Press [Philadelphia], 1906 Feb 18
          See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3316
        - "Peter Newell and His Art" [in Chicago Tribune ?], [1906 Feb 18] (Box 17, Folder 367)
      - "Peter Newell, the Boy Who Never Grew Up" in Northern Valley Times Bulletin [Englewood, NJ], 1906 Dec 20
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3317
      - "Peter Newell" in unknown newspaper, [1910] (Box 17, Folder 368)
      - "Peter Newell" in The Sun [Baltimore], 1910 May 14 (Box 17, Folder 369)
      - "Famous caricaturist lived here years ago" in unknown Illinois newspaper, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 370)
      - "Indiana Artists in the East" in The Indianapolis Sunday Star, 1911 Mar 5
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3318
      - Loomis, Charles B. "Interesting People: Peter Newell" in The American Magazine, 1911 May (Box 17, Folder 371)
      - [Short profile in "People" column of] The National Tribune, Washington, DC, 1911 May 18 (Box 17, Folder 372)
      - "Who Is Peter Newell?" in Macomb Journal [IL], 1911 May 26 (Box 17, Folder 373)
      - "Who Is Peter Newell?" in Daily Republican [IL], 1911 May 27 (Box 17, Folder 374)
      - "Mr. Peter Newell" in Men's Bible Class Sentinel of the First Presbyterian Church of Bushnell, Illinois, 1911 Dec 1 (Box 17, Folder 375)
      - "Peter Newell: Creator of Whimsies" in The Sunday Call [Newark, NJ], 1915 Mar 21
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3319
      - Kilmer, Joyce
        - "Peter Newell Says Domesticity Helps Artists..." in The New York Times Magazine, 1916 Sep 17
          See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3320
        - "Peter Newell Chats About Art of Illustrating" in [Philadelphia] Public Ledger, 1916 Sep 17
        - "Peter Newell," typescript of article published in [Philadelphia] Public Ledger and The New York Times Magazine, [1916] (Box 17, Folder 376)
      - Hofer, Philip "Peter Newell's Pictures and Rhymes" in The Colophon, 1934 Dec (Box 17, Folder 377)
      - Goltra, Mabel Hall "Peter S. Newell, Cartoonist" in Journal of the Illinois State Historical Society, 1948 Jun (Box 17, Folder 378)
      - "Peter Newell, Bushnell's Most Famous Son" in The McDonough Democrat [Bushnell, IL], 1971 May 12 (Box 17, Folder 379)
      - "Heritage Homes" in The McDonough Democrat, 1976 Jul 28 (Box 17, Folder 380)
      - Hearn, Michael Patrick "Peter Newell, American Comic Illustrator" in American Book Collector, 1983 Jul/Aug (Box 17, Folder 381)
    - Mentions and Brief Articles
      - Various articles clipped from papers (primarily Illinois) and pasted on one sheet, 1880s
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3321
      - "Newell's Birthplace" [in unknown Illinois newspaper], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 382)
      - "An Artist's Home at Leonia, New Jersey" in Scientific American, 1898 Jan (Box 17, Folder 383)
      - Carrington, FitzRoy "Subtle Humorists of the Pencil" in The Book Buyer, 1900 Apr (Box 17, Folder 384)
      - Howells, William D. "A Modern Italian View of Humor" in North American Review, 1901 Nov (Box 17, Folder 385)
      - "Peter's Proud Place" [in unknown Illinois newspaper], 1901 Nov (Box 17, Folder 386)
      - "Harper's Bookshelf" [in unknown Harper's publication], 1901 [Nov-Dec] (Box 17, Folder 387)
      - McCardell, Roy L. "With One Hundred and Sixty Real Live Authors All Being Fed at Once at the Banquet to Mark Twain" in The World, 1905 Dec 10
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3322
      - "Bookseller's Banquet" in The New York Sun, 1909 May 13 (Box 17, Folder 388)
      - Speilmann, Marion H. "Caricature" in Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1910-11 (Box 17, Folder 389)
      - "Humorists to the Aid of Humor" (C.B. Loomis testimonial dinner, publication unknown), ca. 1910 (Box 17, Folder 390)
      - "Peter Newell in Bronze" in Harper's Weekly, 1911 Dec 23 (Box 17, Folder 391)
      - "At Close Quarters" (Republican National Convention) in The Globe and Commercial Advertiser [NY], 1912 Jun 17 (Box 17, Folder 392)
      - "Social Circles: Delightful Delphic Morning" in The Paducah Evening Sun [Kentucky], [1914 Mar] (Box 17, Folder 393)
      - "Artistic Artists in a High Revel" in Hackensack Republican [NJ], 1916 Jun 8 (Box 17, Folder 394)
      - Carruth, Hayden "The Postscript" in Woman's Home Companion, 1917 Jan (Box 17, Folder 395)
      - Carruth, Hayden "The Postscript" in Woman's Home Companion, 1929 Dec (Box 17, Folder 396)
      - Woollcott, Alexander in Woollcott's Second Reader, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 397)
      - Dodge, Norman L. "News from the Front" in The Month at Goodspeed's, 1934 Feb (Box 17, Folder 398)
      - Craven, Thomas in Cartoon Cavalcade, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 399)
      - Richardson, Edgar P. in Painting in America, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 400)
      - "Caricature and cartoon" in Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 401)
      - Miscellaneous mentions in "Ripley's Believe It or Not," crossword puzzles and other non-judgmental appearances, [1894]-1985 (Box 17, Folder 402)
    - Reviews and Catalogues of Exhibitions
      - National Academy of Design 68th annual group show, 1893 (Box 18, Folder 403)
      - Atlanta Exposition group show, 1896
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3323
      - Keppel Gallery solo show, 1900 Jan (Box 18, Folder 404)
      - Salmagundi Club group show, 1922-23 (Box 18, Folder 405)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art American watercolors show, 1927 Feb (Box 18, Folder 406)
      - Brooklyn Museum American illustration show, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 407)
    - Reviews and Catalogues of Publications
      - Carrington, J. B. on Tommy Toddles in Clips, 1896 Mar 19 (Box 18, Folder 408)
      - Books & Artistic Publications ®. H. Russell catalogue), 1897 (Box 18, Folder 409)
      - Harper & Brothers Holiday Catalogue (publisher's catalogue), 1899 (Box 18, Folder 410)
      - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, 1901 (Box 18, Folder 411)
      - Newell, Peter "Alice's Adventures in Wonderland from an Artist's Standpoint," in Harper's Monthly Magazine photocopy and typed transcription, 1901 Oct (Box 18, Folder 412)
      - "Christmas Books for Children" "Pictures from the Holiday Books" in The New York Mail and Express Saturday Magazine, 1901 Dec
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3324
      - Henderson, Elliott on Alice's Adventures in Wonderland in "Harper's Bookshelf," Harper's Monthly Magazine, 1902 Jan (Box 18, Folder 413)
      - Mother Goose's Menagerie, 1902 Jan 9 (Box 18, Folder 414)
      - Topsys and Turvys, 1902 Oct-Nov (Box 18, Folder 415)
      - Through the Looking Glass, 1902 Nov-Dec (Box 18, Folder 416)
      - Hunting of the Snark, 1903 (Box 18, Folder 417)
      - Harper's Books for Young People (publisher's catalogue), ca. 1904 (Box 18, Folder 418)
      - Favorite Fairy Tales, 1907 Oct (Box 18, Folder 419)
      - Allen, Philip Loring "The Sketch-books of Wonderland" in The Bookman, 1908 Feb (Box 18, Folder 420)
      - The Hole Book, 1908 Oct 25 (Box 18, Folder 421)
      - Peter Newell Calendar for 1910, 1909 Oct-Dec (Box 18, Folder 422)
      - The Slant Book, with ads, 1910 Nov-Dec (Box 18, Folder 423)
      - Harper's Holiday Books (publisher's catalogue), 1911 (Box 18, Folder 424)
      - Harper's Holiday Books (publisher's catalogue), 1912 (Box 18, Folder 425)
      - Descriptive Catalogue of Books Published by Harper & Brothers (publisher's catalogue), ca. 1913 (Box 18, Folder 426)
      - Bowman, Virginia "Nonsense Books for Children" in The Constitution [Atlanta], 1922 Oct 2 (Box 18, Folder 427)
      - The Christmas Check Book (Harper & Brothers catalogue), 1923 (Box 18, Folder 428)
      - "The Humor of Peter Newell" in The Outlook, 1924 Jan (Box 18, Folder 429)
      - Lewis Carroll books, 1924 Feb-Mar (Box 18, Folder 430)
      - Harper Books for Boys and Girls (publisher's catalogue), 1931 (Box 18, Folder 431)
      - Murrell, William A History of American Graphic Humor, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 432)
      - Ward's Christmas Book (Montgomery Ward catalogue), 1960 (Box 18, Folder 433)
      - Ovendon, Graham, ed. The Illustrators of Alice in Wonderland and Through the Looking Glass, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 434)
      - Miscellaneous, 1899-1905 (Box 18, Folder 435)
    - Parodies